云幕 NAS电影服务器-家庭娱乐管家
本视频为演示影片，仅供交流，观影后请删除！
桥上让道
Make way on the bridge!
作战武器 准备
Battle arms, engage!
凡享受过人脑的僵尸
It is a truth universally acknowledged
总渴求更多的人脑
that a zombie in possession of brains
这已成了一条举世公认的真理
must be in want of more brains.
最近尼日斐花园的惨案
Never was this truth more plain
就是最直白的证明
than in the recent attacs at Netherfield park,
整栋房子的人在惠斯特牌会上
in which an entire household was slaughtered
被一大群活死人屠杀了
by a horde of the living dead during a whist party.
谁在那
Who goes there?
达西
Darcy.
达西上校
Colonel Darcy.
这具纯净年轻的躯体上没有僵尸咬痕
No zombie bite marks on this pristine, young body.
神父
Father.
你怎么能看出我肋骨上的伤口是剑击造成的
How were you able to discern that the wound on my rib was from fencing?
孩子 我干这个很久了
Been at this a long time, my son.
可我没伤口
I have no wound.
金士顿先生 牌叫得真好
Lovely bid, Mr. Kingston!
麻烦给金士顿先生再来些雪利酒
More Sherry for Mr. Kingston please!
费瑟斯通夫人
Mrs. featherstone.
我恐怕达西先生是来这找你的
I'm afraid Mr. Darcy's here to see you, ma'am.
达西?
Darcy?
请继续
Carry on.
我们绝对没什么好隐藏的
We have absolutely nothing to hide.
各位 请尽兴
Please, everyone. Enjoy.
达西先生
Mr. Darcy.
叫我达西上校 费瑟斯通夫人
Colonel Darcy, Mrs. featherstone.
我是来办公事的
I'm here on official business.
有报告说这里有人被咬了
There's been a report that somebody here has been bitten.
肯定没有
Surely not.
哈福德郡有两年多
There hasn't been a zombie incident
没发生过僵尸事件了
in Hertfordshire for over two years.
我向你保证 我们已防范到位
I assure you, we've taken every precaution.
一种新近被感染的僵尸
A newly-infected zombie
几乎不可能被发觉
is almost impossible to detect.
直到他们摄取第一个人脑
Until they've ingested their first human brains,
那时起 转化会随每次后续杀人而加速
at which point, the transformation accelerates with every subsequent kill.
没错 我们都很清楚
Yes. We are all well aware
是怎么回事 达西上校
of how it works, colonel Darcy.
好了 你彻底确信了吗
Well, are you quite satisfied?
没错
Quite.
- 我能玩一把吗 - 当然
- Might I play a hand? - Of course.
晚上好
Good evening.
那我们开始吧
So, shall we?
药剂?
A potion?
是苍蝇 夫人
Flies, ma'am.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
食腐苍蝇
Carrion flies.
它们有一个让人真正羡慕的天赋
They are in possession of but one truly enviable talent.
有寻获腐肉的能力
The ability to detect dead flesh.
我赢了
Well, I've won the trick.
金士顿先生 打得真妙啊
Very crafty play, Mr. Kingston.
我想说 这嗡嗡声响得瘆人
I dare say, the buzzing is frightfully loud.
夫人 你要在意的不该是嗡嗡声
It's not the buzzing that should concern you, madam.
而是嗡嗡声结束的时候
But rather, when the buzzing stops.
天呐
Oh, dear.
一比零 达西
One-nil, Darcy.
我快晕了
I'm going to be faint.
在场还有别人
Is there anyone else present
可能被他感染了吗
whom he would have had the opportunity to infect?
或许他的家人
A family member, perhaps?
晚上愉快
Good evening.
谁竟敢把一个僵尸头
Who would dare just leave a zombie head
留在地板中央
in the middle of the floor?
那是他的头
It's his head!
把它从我面前拿走
Get it away from me.
但金士顿先生的侄女在这里
But Mr. Kingston's niece is here.
没必要把那姑娘
There was no need to put that girl
扯进达西先生的讯问
through Mr. Darcy's interrogation!
卡桑德拉 回来
Cassandra, come back!
安娜贝尔
Annabelle?
你在哪
Where are you?
安娜贝尔
Annabelle?
我亲爱的女儿们 曾经并非总是如此
It wasn't always like this, my dear daughters.
英格兰图解历史 1700年-1800年
自本世纪开始
As the century began,
不列颠尼亚因为全球贸易的成果而富裕
britannia was rich with the fruits of worldwide trade.
人们从殖民地不仅带来了丝绸和香料
From the colonies there came not just silks and spices,
还带来了一种致命可憎的瘟疫
but a virulent and abominable plague.
很多人自然而然地猜疑这是法国人的责任
Naturally, many suspected the French were to blame.
肯定是法国人
Definitely the French.
- 你们意外吗 - 不意外
- Are you surprised? - No.
一被咬
Once bitten,
新近的被感染者便充满了对活人大脑
the newly-infected were filled with an insatiable hunger
无尽的饥饿感
for the brains of the living.
百万人死亡
Millions perished,
却使得难以调和的活死人大军崛起
only to rise again as legions of implacable undead.
这无疑像是世界末日来临了
So certain did it seem the end of days had come
据说连天启四骑士
that even the four horsemen of the apocalypse
也已从地狱升起
are said to have ascended from hell.
为了保护活人 巨垒被建了起来
To protect the living, the grand barrier was built,
一百英尺高的墙围着伦敦
a 100-foot wall encircling London.
之后开凿了皇家运河
Then excavation began on the royal canal,
一个三十英寻深的
a vast moat 30 fathoms deep
巨大运河环绕着城市和城墙
surrounding both the city and its walls.
这两个防御工事之间的陆地
The land twixt the two fortifications became known
后被称为中陆
as the in-between.
这个时期 学习东方的致命之术
At this time, it became fashionable
流行了起来
to study the deadly arts of the orient.
富人去日本
Japan for the wealthy.
智者去中国
China for the wise.
在第二次肯特之战中
In the second battle of Kent,
一座横跨运河的桥被突破了
one of the Bridges across the royal canal was breached.
饥饿的僵尸群屠杀了每一个中陆居民
Ravenous zombie hordes massacred every villager of the in-between.
据说这番杀戮场景让年轻的国王乔治发疯了
It was said, the sight of this slaughter drove young king George mad.
最终打赢这场仗后
When the battle was finally won,
他下令摧毁所有桥梁 只留一座
he ordered the destructin of all the Bridges, save one.
欣厄姆桥
Hingham bridge,
如今 通过皇家运河的
which to this day, remains the only means
- 唯一途径就剩它了 - 那是凯瑟琳夫人
- by which to cross the royal canal. - There's lady Catherine.
很多人相信敌人最终被彻底击败了
Many believed the enemy was finally vanquished.
贵族们开始离开伦敦防卫的安全范围
The gentry began to leave the safe confines of London's defenses
因为他们新筑了防御型田庄
for their newly-fortified country estates.
但警惕仍是重中之重
But vigilance is still of the essence.
切记 将你们的剑同你们的智慧一样保持锋芒
Remember this, keep your swords as sharp as your wit.
因为活人与活死人之间的终极之战
For the ultimate battle between the living and the undead
还未上演
has yet to be staged.
傲慢与偏见与僵尸
译者/微博@Emtee
班内特老爷
Mr. Bennet!
班内特老爷 你有没听闻尼日斐花园又有人入住了
Mr. Bennet, have you heard that Netherfield park is occupied again?
是一位叫宾利的先生
By a Mr. Bingley.
一位很有钱的年轻单身汉
A young, single man of large fortune.
朗夫人说他每年能赚五千英镑
Mrs. long says his income is four or five thousand a year.
他今晚将出席村庄舞会
He is attending the village dance tonight.
这关我们战士般的女儿们什么事
How does this concern our warrior daughters?
你怎么这么讨厌
Oh, how can you be so tiresome?
你知道我希望他娶她们其中一个
You know I mean for him to marry one of them.
班内特太太 女儿们和被吃过的脑子在一起可跳不好舞
Daughters do not dance well with masticated brains, Mrs. Bennet.
老爷 之前你坚持要她们在中国进行格斗修行而非日本
You, sir, have already put them at a decided social disadvantage
已让她们处于
by insisting they do their combat training in China
明显的社交弱势
as opposed to Japan!
中国的致命之术无与伦比
The Chinese deadly arts have no equal.
于我而言 什么都不能替代我的少林修行
I, for one, would trade nothing for my Shaolin training.
丽兹 你不该那样讲话
You mustn't speak like that, lizzy.
我想参加舞会
I should like to go to the dance.
你们觉得宾利先生帅吗
Do you think Mr. Bingley's handsome?
莉迪亚 他那么有钱 就算他有半张僵尸脸 你也会觉得他帅
With his income, Lydia, you'd think him handsome if he had half a zombie face.
不好意思
Sorry.
你会让我非常非常开心的
You'll make me very, very happy.
好吧 我想我们都去的话...
Well, I suppose, if we all go...
不用 我不介意像在农场拍卖行的
No! I don't care to be paraded
一群母牛那样被展示
like a herd of heifers at a farm auction.
那是因为你是头
That's because you're the cow who's least proficient
最不会吸引异性的母牛
in the art of tempting the other sex.
哞
Moo.
别当我宠你们 你们就能放松纪律
Do not mistake my indulgence for a relaxation in discipline!
班内特老爷 她们必须找到丈夫
They must find husbands, Mr. Bennet.
你很清楚 等你过世了 她们什么都继承不了
For as you know too well, they shall inherit nothing when you pass.
目前我只关心她们当下的生存
Their immediate survival is my present concern.
哼
Pish.
要我说 你比这屋里的任何其他女士
Well, I'd say you're easily five times as beautiful
都漂亮五倍
as any other woman in this room.
丽兹 别这么说
Stop it, Liz.
真的
It's true.
这些姑娘毫无机会
These girls don't stand a chance.
据说宾利先生带了一群伦敦的时髦男子过来
They say Mr. Bingley brought a tribe of London dandies with him.
- 丽兹 微笑啊 - 待会儿会笑的
- Smile, Liz. - I will later.
那是尼日斐花园帅气的新主人
There's the handsome new master of Netherfield.
在哪
Oh! Where?
据我所知 宾利上尉想要娶位妻子
It was my understanding that captain Bingley was in want of a wife.
是的
Oh, he is.
那两个是他的姐妹 卡罗琳·宾利和路易莎·赫斯特
Those are his sisters, Caroline Bingley and Louisa hurst.
据说他继承了近十万英镑
They say he inherited nearly £100,000.
他会是个多么了不起的丈夫啊
What a magnificent husband he'd make.
夏洛特·卢卡斯 你脑子里就没别的了吗
Charlotte Lucas, do you think of nothing else?
丽兹 不管有没僵尸 所有女人都必须考虑婚姻
Zombies or no zombies, all women must think of marriage, lizzy.
我绝不会为一枚戒指而放弃我的剑
I shall never relinquish my sword for a ring.
有了对的男人 你会的
For the right man, you would.
对的男人不会要我那么做
The right man wouldn't ask me to.
达西先生 仪表堂堂
Mr. Darcy. Rather an imposing presence.
德贝郡有一半是他的 年收入至少一万英镑
Owns half of derbyshire. £10,000 a year, at least.
什么
What?
夏洛特·卢卡斯 回你的家人那儿去
Back to your own family, Charlotte Lucas.
丽兹 你看上去很漂亮
Now, Liz, you look very nice.
谢谢 别搞得那么惊讶
Well, thank you. Don't act so surprised.
行了 行了 行了 微笑
Out, out. Out. Smile.
欢迎 亲爱的朋友
Welcome, dear friend.
- 你好 - 你怎么样 查尔斯
- How are you? - How are you, Charles?
我很好 从德贝郡来的路上怎么样
I'm very well. How was the journey from derbyshire?
- 挺好 - 那就好
- Fine. - Good.
所以这里就是麦里屯?
So this is meryton?
我从没见过她这么美丽的尤物
She's the most beautiful creature i ever beheld.
她笑得太多了
She smiles too much.
她...她是位天使
She... She's an angel.
天呐
Oh, my word.
我是查尔斯·宾利 很高兴与你们相识
Charles Bingley, pleased to make your acquaintance.
我是班内特夫人 宾利先生 我们对你久仰大名
Mrs. Bennet. We've heard so much about you, Mr. Bingley.
我的女儿们 全都完美无瑕
My daughters, all of impeccable character.
请允许我介绍我的朋友 德贝郡的达西先生
Well... May I introduce my friend, Mr. Darcy of derbyshire!
宾利先生 你喜欢哈福德郡吗
Are you enjoying Hertfordshire, Mr. Bingley?
非常喜欢
Very much.
我听说尼日斐的图书馆是最好的之一
I've heard the library at Netherfield is one of the finest.
图...图书馆?是吗
Li...library? Is it?
班内特小姐 我能斗胆请你跳下面两支舞吗
Miss Bennet, may I be so bold as to request the next two dances?
如果你没另外有人的话
If you are not otherwise engaged.
我没
I am not engaged.
宾利先生 好眼光
Good for you, Mr. Bingley.
你选了我最美的女儿
You chose the loveliest of my daughters.
- 母亲 - 好啦...
- Mother! - Well...
我认为跳舞是上流社会最出色的才艺
I consider dancing to be the first refinement of polished society.
达西先生 你同意吗
Don't you agree, Mr. Darcy?
现在哪个野蛮人不会跳舞
Now every savage can dance.
我想僵尸们也能成功跳上一两步
Why, I imagine even zombies could do it to some degree of success.
晚上愉快
Good evening.
实际上 我也喜欢看书
You know, I love to read, too, actually.
我看过很多书
I have read.
班内特小姐 请别忘了我们的下一支舞
Please don't forget our next dance, miss Bennet.
达西 我讨厌看到你就光站在那儿 你一定要跳舞
Darcy, I hate to see you just standing there. You must dance.
你知道我讨厌和不熟的人跳舞
Oh, you know I detest it when I'm not acquainted with my partner.
- 这样的话... - 达西
- Oh, well... - Darcy.
你有这里唯一漂亮的姑娘和你跳
You are dancing with the only handsome girl here.
但她有一个妹妹也非常漂亮
Oh, but one of her sisters is also very pretty.
我敢说 很讨人喜爱
Dare I say, very agreeable.
- 好吧 她也就那样 但... - 也就那样?
Well, she's tolerable but... Tolerable?
是的 也就那样
Yes, tolerable.
但还没漂亮到能吸引我
But not handsome enough to tempt me.
显然也没能吸引这里的任何其他男士
Nor any other man here, apparently.
达西 我亲爱的伙计 你的标准...
Darcy, your standards, my dear fellow...
真是倒霉
Oh, that is unfortunate.
好失态
What a lack of grace.
达西先生 你自命清高得让人厌恶
Mr. Darcy, you're an insufferable prig.
菲茨威廉·达西?
Fitzwilliam Darcy?
我相当厌恶这个人
I quite detest the man.
那么高傲 那么自负 我受不了他
So high and so conceited that I can't endure him.
确实
Indeed.
我不会和他跳舞 如果他...
I wouldn't dance with him if he were...
费瑟斯通夫人?
Mrs. featherstone?
你成活死人了
You're undead.
我是来告诉你...
I've come to tell you...
丽兹 发生什么事了
What happened, lizzy?
我侥幸救了她的命
I narrowly saved her life.
那是费瑟斯通夫人
From Mrs. featherstone?
那可是活死人费瑟斯通夫人
From an undead Mrs. featherstone.
我觉得她完完全全也就那样啊
I found her to be exceedingly tolerable.
干得好 达西 非常英勇
Well done, Darcy. Very heroic.
她想告诉我些什么
She was trying to tell me something.
或许一份食谱吧?
A recipe, perhaps?
随你怎么取笑吧
Laugh as much as you choose.
不过你笑不掉我的看法
But you shall not laugh me out of my opinion.
她构不成威胁
She posed no threat.
我们正受到攻击
We are under attack!
女士们
Ladies!
她那双乌黑的眼睛美丽非凡
Her face is rendered uncommonly intelligent
使她的脸蛋显得极其聪慧
by the beautiful expression of her dark eyes.
我不得不承认她体态轻盈 惹人喜爱
And I'm forced to acknowledge her figure as both light and pleasing.
她的手臂出人意料的强壮
And that her arms are surprisingly muscular,
但又不失女性的柔美
yet not so much as to be unfeminine.
丽兹 我从没见过那样讨人喜欢的举止
Oh, lizzy, i never saw such happy manners.
好大方 好有教养
So much ease with such good breeding.
我不反对你喜欢他
I give you leave to like him.
反正你喜欢过很多更蠢的人
You've liked many a stupider person.
他有年轻男子该具备的样子
He's just what a young man ought to be.
风趣 活泼 英俊 还有...
Good-humored, lively, handsome, and...
相当富有 这也是一个年轻男子该具备的
Quite rich, which a young man ought likewise to be,
如果他可能做到的话
if he possibly can.
没达西那么富有
Not as rich as Darcy.
他一走进舞会时
I saw how you looked at him
我看到了你看他的眼神
when he first walked in the dance...
我讨厌他的眼神?
As if I hated him?
你喜欢他的眼神
As if you liked him.
那是在他的言行让我厌恶之前的事了
Until his manners gave me disgust!
他表现得就像瞧不起人 难以被取悦似的
He acted as if he were above our company and above being pleased.
承认你觉得他帅吧
Admit you find him handsome.
内心美好才是真的帅
Handsome is as handsome does.
因此达西先生是个很丑的人
Mr. Darcy is therefore a very ill-looking man.
姑娘们 房子快被你们拆了
Girls, you will knock the house down!
我从没见过如此沉溺于他自己傲慢之中的人
Never have i encountered a man so consumed by his own pride!
这么优秀的一个年轻男子
One cannot wonder that so very fine a young man
门第好 又有钱 样样都比别人强
with family, fortune, and everything in his favor
也难怪自视甚高
should think highly of himself.
要我说
If I may so express it,
他有权傲慢
he has a right to be proud.
如果他没触犯我的傲慢
I could easily forgive his pride,
那我能很容易原谅他的
if he had not mortified mine.
我相信傲慢是一般人的通病
Pride is a very common failing, i believe.
自负和傲慢是不同的东西
Vanity and pride are different things,
尽管它们常被当作同义词用
though the words are often used synonymously.
一个人或许能傲慢而不自负
A person may be proud without being vain.
傲慢更多在于我们对我们自己的看法
Pride relates more to our opinion of ourselves,
自负则是我们给别人的看法
and vanity to what we would have others think of us.
给珍·班内特小姐的信
A letter for miss Jane Bennet.
他把你从一个僵尸那儿救下
He saved you from a zombie.
费瑟斯通夫人相当文明
Mrs. featherstone was quite civilized.
- 认输吧 - 绝不
- Yield! - Never!
丽兹 她是个僵尸 谢天谢地 他当时在场
She was a zombie, lizzy. Thank goodness he was there.
丽兹
Lizzy!
别啊 丽兹
No, lizzy!
- 别 别 别 别这样 丽兹 - 那不公平
- No, no, no! Stop it, lizzy! - That's not fair!
莉迪亚
Lydia!
宾利家邀请我去喝茶
The bingleys have invited me to tea.
- 莉迪亚 来 - 他们当然会了
- Lydia, come on. - Well, of course they have.
没错 下面
Yeah. Down there.
怎么了
What?
说真的 我更想坐马车去
Truly, I'd much rather go by coach.
你骑马去更好
You had much better go on horseback,
因为看上去要下雨了
for it seems likely to rain,
那样你就能过夜了
and then you must stay all night.
这倒是个好办法
That would be a good scheme,
只要你拿得准他们不会送她回来
if you were sure they would not send her home.
母亲 我真的更想坐马车
Mother, I really would prefer the carriage.
珍 女人十之有九会流露出
Jane, Mr. Bingley undoubtedly likes you.
比内心更强烈的情意
But in nine cases out of 10,
宾利先生毫无疑问是喜欢你的
a woman had far better show more affection than she feels.
够了
Enough.
现在快走吧 僵尸在湿润的土地上更容易移动
Go quickly now. The zombies spring easily from the wet earth.
仁慈的上帝啊
Merciful god.
这不可能
This cannot be.
她在哪
Where is she?
她必须时刻受到密切监视
She must be closely monitored
并被锁在房里
and her room locked at all times...
达西 这有点过了
That is a little excessive, Darcy.
伊丽莎白·班内特小姐来了
Miss Elizabeth Bennet.
你一路走来的吗
Did you walk all the way here?
是的 我姐姐怎么样了
Yes. How is my sister?
她昨晚发烧了 还睡不好
She was feverish and slept ill last night.
我恐怕她得了流感
I fear she has the flu.
或更糟
Or worse.
我讨厌病患 让人一直处于不雅的状态
I detest illness. It keeps one in a continual state of inelegance.
没错
Quite.
我能看她吗
May I tend to her?
当然能 埃德温 给班内特小姐带路
Of course. Edwin, show miss Bennet the way.
谢谢
Thank you.
宾利 我在费瑟斯通夫人的
I will not make the same mistake I made
惠斯特牌会上犯的错 我不会再犯
at Mrs. featherstone's whist party, Bingley.
珍妮
Oh, janey.
班内特小姐
Miss Bennet.
医生到了
The physician has arrived.
麻烦了
Please.
她被暴雨淋了?
She got caught in the downpour?
是的
Yes.
医生 看下伤口
The wound, doctor.
她的毛瑟枪回火了
Her musket backfired.
我没看到有被咬的迹象
I see no indication of a bite.
这一点根本不用顾虑
That was never in question.
我相信它们是你的
I believe that these belong to you.
达西 老兄 你看上去差不多很失望啊
Darcy, old bean, you almost seem disappointed.
路易莎 你不该出那张黑桃
Louisa, you shouldn't have played that spade.
我赢了 我赢了
I won! I won!
她怎么样了
How is she?
她睡得很熟
She's fast asleep.
我肯定她会好的 班内特小姐 请加入我们吧
I'm sure she'll be quite well. Please join us, miss Bennet.
谢谢 不过我会找本书消遣
Thank you, but I'll amuse myself with a book.
你宁可看书 不要玩牌吗
You prefer reading to cards?
赫斯特先生 比起玩牌 我还有许多更喜欢的东西
I prefer a great many things to cards, Mr. hurst.
世界上有一半人不理解另一半人的乐趣
One half of the world cannot understand the pleasures of the other.
我不会日语
I don't speak Japanese.
当然了 你不是在日本修行的
No, of course. You didn't train in Japan.
是在中国 对吗
China, was it?
河南省少林寺
The Shaolin temple in henan province.
在那里 我学会了忍受各种不适感
It was there that i learned to endure all manner of discomfort.
我能问问这种不适感的本质是什么吗
May I inquire as to the nature of this discomfort?
我更乐意示范给你看
I would much rather give you a demonstration.
达西先生 自春天以来 你妹妹是不是长高了很多
Mr. Darcy, is your sister much grown since the spring?
她现在差不多有伊丽莎白·班内特小姐这么高
She is now about the same height as miss Elizabeth Bennet.
真不敢相信我见过
I don't believe I've ever met a girl
一个如此多才多艺的姑娘
who was so extremely accomplished.
"多才多艺"这个词 如今被滥用于称赞年轻女士 但是...
The word "accomplished" is far too liberally applied to young ladies today,but...
我的妹妹乔治亚娜的确配得上此等称赞
my sister georgiana does deserve that distinction.
因为她不仅精通女性技艺 还精通致命之术
Not only is she a master of the female arts but the deadly as well.
不是我说大话 但我认识的所有女人中
I cannot boast of knowing more than half a dozen
算得上多才多艺的 不超过六个
in the whole range of my acquaintance that is thus accomplished.
我肯定我这也是
Nor I, I'm sure.
那么 达西先生
Then, Mr. Darcy,
在你的理解中 一个多才多艺的女人
you must comprehend a great deal in your idea
必定有着很多能耐
of an accomplished woman.
是的
I do.
一个女人必须非常精通音乐 唱歌
A woman must have a thorough knowledge of music, singing,
绘画 舞蹈 和现代语言
drawing, dancing and the modern languages.
她必须很好地修炼过众多京都大师的格斗风格
She must be well-trained in the fighting styles of the Kyoto masters,
并精通众多现代欧洲的武器和兵法
and the weapons and tactics of modern Europe.
否则就配不上那个词
Or the term would only be half-deserved.
而你认识六个这样的女人?
And you know six such women?
可我现在怀疑你一个都不认识
I wonder now at your knowing any.
你如此小看你自己的同性人群吗
Are you so severe on your own sex?
一个女人要么素养极高 要么优雅至极
A woman is either highly trained or highly refined.
在这样的年代 没人能两者兼具
One cannot afford the luxury of both in such times.
孙子兵法[法语]
L'art de la guerre.
孙子兵法
The art of war.
你没读过原来的吴语方言版吗
Have you not read it in its original wu dialect?
没有
Alas.
那你等于没读过孙子兵法
Then you've never read the art of war.
我该回珍那儿了
I should get back to Jane.
她是那种通过贬低
She is one of those young ladies
自己同性人群 以在男人们面前
who seeks to recommend themselves to men
自抬身价的年轻女人之一
by undervaluing their own sex.
毋庸置疑
Undoubtedly.
我不想说谎...
I'm not going to lie...
天呐 姑娘们
Oh, my word, girls,
看看这里复园后变得多豪华啊
regard how opulently reappointed it has been.
他肯定比我们想象的更富有
He must be even more wealthy than we imagined.
把僵尸血从大理石上清除
It would have cost a small fortune, of course,
一定花了一小笔钱
to get the zombie blood out of the marble.
班内特夫人 班内特小姐
Mrs. Bennet, miss Bennet,
班内特小姐和班内特小姐来了
miss Bennet and miss Bennet.
班内特夫人 很高兴见到你
Mrs. Bennet, i am so glad to see you.
很遗憾发生这种让人烦恼的事
Oh, and sadly at distressing circumstances.
你是来带珍回家的吗
Are you here to take Jane home?
- 不是 - 是的
- No. - Yes!
我们不能再麻烦你了
We must not trespass any longer on your kindness.
想必她病得太重 不好被转移
Surely, she is too ill to be moved.
她确实看上去面无血色
She... She does look very pale.
- 宾利 - 我坚决反对
- Bingley. - I must protest.
宾利 别这样
Bingley, please.
不留心对待僵尸感染
Carelessness when dealing with a zombie infection
会致你意外身亡
could lead to your abrupt demise.
自大会致你意外身亡
Arrogance could lead to yours.
班内特小姐 你的缺点 除了偷听外
Your defect, miss Bennet, besides eavesdropping,
就是故意误解他人
is to willfully misunderstand people.
而你的缺点就是对他人有不公的偏见
And yours is to be unjustly prejudiced against them.
走吧 伊丽莎 走吧
Come on, Eliza. Come on.
宾利先生 我知道怎么打破
Mr. Bingley, i know just the thing
这种极度紧张的氛围
to break this terrible tension and...
让郡上的人振作精神
And lift the spirits of the county.
在尼日斐办一次舞会
A ball at Netherfield.
想都别想
Out of the question.
安全没保障...
The security arrangements alone...
真是个好主意
It's a brilliant idea.
等珍妮康复了 请你指定日期
When Jane is recovered you shall, if you please, name the day.
我很荣幸
I should be honored.
好了
All right.
瞧瞧她
Look at her.
我们本可以在那栋豪宅住上一个星期
We could've stayed on for another week in that palace.
就算感冒 也好过被达西拔刀相向
I'd risk a cold before I'd risk Darcy's blade.
比彻姆夫人的孤儿院陷落了
Oh, Mrs. beacham's orphanage fell.
今晚的家宴会多一个人
There will be an addition to our party for dinner tonight.
看来你彻底恢复健康了
It would appear your health is fully restored.
完全康复了 爸爸
Quite recovered, papa.
我不知道有人要来
I know of no one who is coming.
我说的这个人
The person of whom I speak
是某位先生
is a certain gentleman.
让我看看
Let me see.
那是谁
Who is it?
"某位先生"
"A certain gentleman."
这讨厌的家伙在干什么
What is that odious man doing?
他在仔细查看他未来的财产
He is perusing his future property.
听着 这个庄园依法必须传给男性继承者
See, this estate must, by law, go to a male heir.
我一死 那个"讨厌的家伙" 柯林斯先生
Now that "odious man," Mr. Collins,
可以随他高兴地
may, the moment i am dead,
把你们赶出这栋房子
toss you all out of this house at his pleasure.
告诉我 我该赞美我的哪位漂亮表妹
Tell me, to which of my fair cousins do I owe the compliments
这厨艺太 我再说一遍 这高超的厨艺
of the excellent, and I repeat, excellent cooking?
先生 我的女儿们受的是战斗训练 而非下厨训练
My daughters were trained for battle, sir. Not the kitchen.
没错 班内特先生
Quite, Mr. Bennet.
我的女资助人不仅是国王麾下最富有的臣民
My patroness is not only the king's richest subject,
还是最致命的
but deadliest.
异常致力于歼灭活死人
Singularly dedicated to the annihilation of the undead.
我想你们都听说过凯瑟琳·德·包尔夫人吧
I assume you have all heard of lady Catherine de bourgh?
她是整个大不列颠最致命的女剑客
She's the most deadly swordswoman in all of Great Britain.
有着黑豹的敏捷
With the agility of a black panther.
我的寒舍毗邻夫人阁下的住所 罗新斯花园
My humble abode abuts her ladyship's estate, rosings park.
她结婚了吗
Was she ever married?
很遗憾 是寡妇 她有一个女儿 安 可惜体弱多病
Widow, sadly.She has one daughter, Anne, who is unfortunately of a sickly constitution.
安进宫了吗
Has Anne been presented?
没有 班内特夫人
Oh, no. No, Mrs. Bennet.
她体质孱弱 没法进宫
Her ill health prevents it.
我跟凯瑟琳夫人说 这让宫廷
I told lady Catherine that the court has been deprived
损失了一颗最璀璨的明珠
of its brightest ornament.
你们瞧 奉上这些自然而发且非常精妙的恭维话
I have a talent, you see, for delivering these very delicate compliments
是我的天赋
with an unstudied air.
先生 你现在所缺的似乎是一名妻子
It would seem, sir, that all you lack now is a wife.
班内特夫人 我必须承认
I must confess, Mrs. Bennet,
最适合做妻子的人选就在这间屋子里
the fairest wifely choices be right here in this room.
我宣布 我
I declare that I am
着迷于你的女儿 珍
enchanted by your daughter, Jane.
我请求和她私下谈话 如果可以的话
And request to speak to her alone, if I may.
亲爱的牧师
Oh, dear parson.
我恐怕珍已被人相中
I'm afraid Jane is already spoken for.
我们迫切地期待着她被正式求婚
We expect a serious proposal imminently.
真糟糕
Oh, fuddle.
但丽兹完全单身
But Liz is quite available,
几乎和珍一样合适
and almost as fair as Jane.
什么
What?
珍真的是毫无商量余地吗
Is there absolutely no negotiating over Jane?
- 柯林斯先生 早起的鸟儿有虫吃 - 确实
- The early bird catches the worm, Mr. Collins. - Oh, indeed.
先生 别忘了你在精妙恭维话上的天赋
Be mindful of your talent for the delicate compliment, sir.
是啊 是啊
Oh, no. Yeah... Why, yes...
她几乎和另一个一样合适
She is almost as fair as the other one.
太棒了
Splendid.
谢谢 女士们
Thank you, ladies.
安下心来
Settle down.
我想今早
Now, I thought this morning,
我可以给你们读弗迪斯的《给年轻女士们的讲道集》
I might read to you from fordyce's sermons to young women.
- 真是难得 - 真是难得
- What a treat. - What a treat.
第一章 家
"Chapter one, the home."
我们要走去麦里屯拜访菲利普斯姨妈
We're walking to meryton to visit aunt Phillips.
只要珍和丽兹愿意陪你们
So long as Jane and lizzy are willing to accompany you.
我们当然愿意
We most certainly are.
当然还有柯林斯先生
And, er, Mr. Collins, of course.
我很乐意
Well, I should be delighted,
除非班内特先生同意我不用读了
but only if Mr. Bennet will consent to release me from my reading.
先生 我勉为其难吧
With a heavy heart, sir.
班内特先生 我容易被讨好
Mr. Bennet, I am susceptible to flattery,
而先生你 非常洒脱
and you, sir, are very charming.
走吧 女士们
Come along, ladies.
伊丽莎白小姐 你今天看上去真迷人
Miss Elizabeth, how charming you look today.
我们去看看麦里屯的商店橱窗
Let us look in the shop windows of meryton
买些新的锅碗瓢盆
and we can buy some new pots and pans
换掉你的剑和匕首
to take the place of your swords and daggers.
是有什么麻烦吗
Is there some sort of trouble?
显然是的
Oh, it appears there is.
佩妮·麦格雷戈的马车
Penny McGregor's carriage.
救命
Help!
有人被困在里面了
Someone's trapped inside.
- 珍 - 救命
- Jane. - Please!
出了起事故
There's been an accident!
救救我 来人啊 救命
Please help me! Anyone! Please!
救命
Help!
出了起可怕的事故
There was a horrible accident,
但我幸存了
but I survived.
我幸存了 珍妮
I survived, janey.
不是传统意义上的幸存
Not in the traditional sense of the word.
看来麦格雷戈小姐不会再递送灯油了
It appears miss McGregor won't be delivering any more lamp oil.
我必须承认
I must confess,
我不知道僵尸
I was unaware that zombies possessed
能灵敏到设置这样的陷阱
the required acuity to set such traps.
他们要在我们不知不觉中竞选议会了吧
Before we know it, they'll be running for parliament.
走吧
Come along.
太好了 实际上我们一定要试试午前茶点
Fantastic. We must try and make elevenses, actually.
快点 伊丽莎白 我们绝不能磨蹭 我们不能迟到
Come along, Elizabeth. We mustn't dawdle, we can't be late.
班内特小姐
Miss Bennet.
谢谢 柯林斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Collins.
请允许我帮下忙
Allow me.
绅士风度可没消失 快 快 我们一定不能迟到
Gallantry isn't dead. Come, come now. We mustn't be late.
警惕僵尸
Keep your eyes peeled for zombies!
不准单独走动
No one walks alone!
这些一定是他们
This must be the extra militia
驻扎在麦里屯的额外民兵
they stationed here in meryton.
吉蒂 看他啊
Oh, kitty, look at him.
好啊 你们怎么样
Good day. How are you?
我是吉蒂 这是莉迪亚 嗨
Kitty. Lydia. Hi.
丹尼中尉
Lieutenant Denny!
和他一起的是谁
Who's that with him?
莉迪亚·班内特小姐和凯瑟琳·班内特小姐 韦翰中尉
Miss Lydia Bennet and miss Catherine Bennet. Lieutenant wickham,
他刚被派到我们的麦里屯兵团
who has just been assigned to our meryton regiment
来处理僵尸回潮
to deal with the zombie resurgence.
我打赌你是兵团里的大帅哥
I bet you're fearful handsome in your regimentals.
吉蒂 莉迪亚
Kitty, Lydia.
珍·班内特小姐 伊丽莎白·班内特小姐 请允许我介绍...
Miss Jane Bennet, miss Elizabeth Bennet, may I introduce...
- 乔治·韦翰 - 他是名中尉
- George wickham. - He's a lieutenant.
这位是我们的表哥 柯林斯先生
This is our cousin, Mr. Collins.
柯林斯牧师
Parson Collins.
我们去菲利普斯家没迟到吗
Aren't we overdue at the Phillips'?
和我们走吧
Walk us.
我恐怕我有约在先了
I fear I have a prior engagement.
韦翰先生?
Mr. wickham?
好的 很乐意
Yes. Enchanted.
她在烘烤了
She is baking,
- 所以我们一定不能迟到 - 莉迪亚
- so we mustn't be late. - Lydia.
我说她在烘烤了
I said she is baking.
我很想准时到
I was very keen to be on time
因为菲利普斯姨妈的松饼显然非常棒
because, apparently, aunt Phillips' muffins are splendid, you see.
是吗
Is that so?
没错 凯瑟琳夫人痛恨迟到
Yeah, and lady Catherine herself abhors tardiness,
实际上这让我被灌输了做事有序的观念
and actually it's instilled me with a real sense of order.
谢谢你陪同我们
Thank you for accompanying us
也谢谢你包容我的妹妹们
and enduring my younger sisters.
不客气
It's my pleasure.
韦翰先生 整个冬季 你都会驻扎在这吗
Are you going to be stationed here all winter, Mr. wickham?
班内特小姐 那完全要看
Well, that depends entirely on what the manky dreadfuls
我们将遇到什么样的骇人邪物
have in store for us, miss Bennet.
宾利先生
Mr. Bingley.
我们正要赶去朗伯恩
We were just on our way to longbourn.
宾利先生 你答应会在
Mr. Bingley, you promised
尼日斐办舞会
you'd throw a ball at Netherfield.
- 你完全康复了吗 - 她康复了
- Are you quite recovered? - She is.
那我要马上开始准备
Then I shall begin the preparations immediately
哈福德郡从未有过的最光彩的舞会
for the most glorious ball Hertfordshire has ever seen.
韦翰中尉能来吗
Can lieutenant wickham come?
当然 我的所有同僚都会收到邀请
Of course, an invitation shall be sent to all my fellow officers.
我失陪了
Excuse me.
再见 珍小姐
Good day, miss Jane.
你们在那啊 我美丽的侄女们
There you are, my beautiful nieces.
韦翰先生 请和我们来吧
Please join us, Mr. wickham.
不了 我恐怕有职责在身
No. Duty calls, I'm afraid.
韦翰先生 我很想知道
I must know, Mr. wickham,
你和达西先生之间有什么问题
what is amiss between you and Mr. Darcy?
你很熟悉他吗
Are you much acquainted with him?
不熟悉也难
More than I wish to be.
他来这里不到一个月
He's been here for less than a month
已经成了郡里最不受欢迎的人
and is already the least popular man in the county.
是啊 每次看到他 总使我很痛苦
Yes, it always gives me great pain to see him.
我还在襁褓里时就和他家有关系了
I have been connected with his family from infancy.
我父亲曾负责管理老达西先生的庄园
My father managed the late Mr. Darcy's estate.
达西和我是一起长大的
Darcy and i grew up together.
他父亲待我如同他的第二个儿子
His father treated me like a second son.
他对我的好 我无法形容
I cannot begin to do justice to his kindness.
他在遗嘱上说 把最好的牧师职位给我
He bequeathed me with the best living in his gift.
我曾渴望加入教会
I had my heart set on joining the church.
但他在第二次肯特之战被杀后
But when he was slain in the second battle of Kent,
达西无视了他的遗嘱 把我的牧师职位给了另一个人
Darcy ignored his wishes and gave my living to another man.
是什么致使他如此无情地对你
What could have induced him to behave so cruelly?
傲慢
Pride.
他认为我地位低 不值得考虑
He thought me too low to be worth his consideration.
我深爱他的父亲 所以我绝不能揭发达西
I loved his father dearly, so, I can never expose Darcy
或是找他决斗
or challenge him to a duel.
丽兹 快来
Come now, lizzy!
我们必须计划下我们的北部之行
We must plan our trip to the north country.
我就来
I'll be right there.
或许我会在宾利先生的舞会上见到你?
Well, perhaps I shall see you at Mr. Bingley's ball?
或许吧
Perhaps.
我会去的
I'll be there.
天呐
Oh, dear.
对不起
Beg your pardon.
韦翰先生 你来了
Mr. wickham, you came.
如我所言 我会来
As I said I would.
我还担心有达西先生在 你不会来
I feared that Mr. Darcy's presence would keep you away.
达西想避开我的话 该走的是他 不是我
If Darcy wishes to avoid me, he must go, not I.
班内特小姐 我找到你了
I have found you, miss Bennet!
抱歉 你是?
Sorry, and you are?
韦翰
Wickham.
韦翰先生啊 容貌如班内特小姐这样
Oh, Mr. wickham. I never forget a face,
犹若天使的 我倒绝不会忘
especially one as angelic as miss Bennet's.
但愿你没忘记我们要跳舞
I do hope you haven't forgotten our dance?
当然没 柯林斯牧师
Of course not, parson Collins.
我来拿吧
Oh, allow me.
谢谢 韦翰先生
Thank you, Mr. wickham.
凯瑟琳夫人亲自夸过我的轻盈舞步
Lady Catherine herself has praised me on my lightness of foot.
先生 我好奇如此精妙的步伐
Wonder, sir, how you found the time
你是怎么找到时机练的
to hone such delicacy in your steps.
班内特小姐 奉承会让你无事不成
Flattery will get you everywhere, miss Bennet.
亲爱的...
Dear...
舞蹈似乎越来越远离我们
The dance seems to be getting away with us.
我认为每个神职人员理所应当
I think it only right and proper that every clergyman
在教区为婚姻生活做榜样
should set the example for matrimony in the parish.
这是我最爱的舞蹈时刻
This is my favorite moment of the dance.
现在舞会到达了高潮
And now the party's in full swing.
光辉四溢
Such splendor in the air.
我的漂亮表妹
A parson may no longer lead
一个牧师不会再过朴素的生活
a chaste life, my fair cousin.
柯林斯先生 请小声点
Mr. Collins, please keep your voice down.
太棒了
Splendid.
各位 跳得太棒了
Splendid work, everyone.
谢谢你们的关注
Thank you for your attention.
大家都跳得很大胆
Everyone did valiantly.
班内特小姐 我想整晚
Miss Bennet, it is my intention to remain very close to you
都在你身边
throughout all the evening.
- 我能跳下一支舞吗 - 能
- May I have the next dance? - Yes.
达西先生 这是柯林斯先生
Mr. Darcy, this is Mr. Collins.
- 柯林斯牧师 - 柯林斯牧师
- Parson Collins. - Parson Collins.
你的...
Your...
他是我的表哥
Uh... he's my cousin.
达西先生 我有个最难以置信的发现
Mr. Darcy, I have made the most incredible discovery...
不对 是卓绝非凡的发现 先生
Nay. Tosh. An extraordinary discovery, sir.
你是凯瑟琳·德·包尔夫人的侄子
You are the nephew of lady Catherine de bourgh.
我知道
I know.
我知道你知道
Well, I know you know.
- 请允许我荣幸地介绍自己... - 请恕我失陪
- Allow me to do the honor of introducing myself... - Please excuse me.
请恕我失陪
Please excuse me.
我是柯林斯牧师
I am parson Collins.
我的寒舍毗邻夫人阁下的...
My humble abode abuts her ladyship's...
我预测婚礼会在三个月内举行
I predict a wedding in under three months.
他是个如此英俊的年轻男子
He's such a charming young man,
如此...
and so...
富有
Well, rich.
珍嫁给宾利必然会让她的妹妹们遇到
Jane marrying Bingley is bound to throw her younger sisters
其他富人
in the way of other rich men.
然后...
And then...
母亲 该走了
Mother, it's time to go.
别这么粗鲁
Don't be so impertinent.
达西先生听见你的话了
Mr. Darcy heard you.
达西先生跟我有什么关系 我干嘛要怕他
What is Mr. Darcy to me, pray, that I should be afraid of him?
我到处都找不到爸爸和莉迪亚
I can't find papa or Lydia anywhere.
爸爸在图书馆吧
Papa will be in the library
我去找那个蠢丫头
and I'll find that stupid girl.
埃德温 甜点呢
Edwin, where is dessert?
你好 班内特夫人...小姐
Hello, Mrs... Hello, miss Bennett.
先生?
Sir?
我们必须立即找到达西
We must find Darcy immediately.
来不及了
There's no time.
宾利先生
Mr. Bingley.
当然了
Yes.
所有的灯都被熄灭了
All the lanterns have been snuffed out.
班内特小姐 注意脚下
Oh, mind your step, miss Bennet.
宾利先生
Mr. Bingley.
你们是比彻姆夫人的孤儿
You're Mrs. beacham's orphans.
班内特小姐 我们曾经是
We were, miss Bennet.
你们怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
我们的新朋友给我们指了路
Our new friend showed us the way in.
达西先生
Mr. Darcy!
他被咬了吗
Was he bitten?
- 他被咬了吗 - 没
- Was he bitten? - No.
没 他摔倒撞了头
No, he fell and hit his head.
宾利
Bingley.
宾利 醒醒
Bingley, wake up.
来 伙计
Come on, chap.
达西先生 你是一名出色的战士
Your abilities as a warrior are beyond reproach, Mr. Darcy.
要是你对朋友也那么出色就好了
If only you were as good a friend.
亲爱的珍 我们决定关闭尼日斐
"Dear Jane, we have decided to close down Netherfield
返回伦敦
"and return to London.
我们不知道什么时候回来
"We are not sure when we shall return."
宾利家就这样关门离开了?
The bingleys just closed down the house and left?
我不明白 为什么他不知道什么时候回来
I don't understand. Why would he not know when he is to return?
按卡罗琳·宾利的说法
According to Caroline Bingley,
达西先生急着要去见他妹妹
"Mr. Darcy is impatient to see his sister.
我的哥哥已深深为她倾倒
"My brother admires her greatly already.
现在起 他会以最亲密的
"He will now be seeing her frequently
身份去时常看她
"and on the most intimate footing.
我最亲爱的珍 我由衷希望这件事
"Am I wrong, my dearest Jane, in indulging the hope of an event
能成全众多人的幸福 我有错吗
"which will secure the happiness of so many?"
显然她知道她的哥哥爱上了你
Obviously, she knows her brother is in love with you,
可她希望他娶达西小姐
and wants him to marry miss Darcy.
如果宾利先生真的爱我 那么没什么能把我们分开
If Mr. Bingley truly loves me, nothing can keep us apart.
凡见过你俩在一起的人 都不会怀疑他的感情
No one who has ever seen you together can doubt his affection.
我肯定宾利先生会很快回来
I'm sure Mr. Bingley will be back soon.
而这一切都是有原因的
And that there's a good reason for all this.
女士们
Ladies.
女士们 早上好
Good morrow.
柯林斯先生 想跟你们的姐姐私下谈话
Mr. Collins would like a private audience with your sister.
莉迪亚
Lydia.
- 什么 和丽兹? - 出去 出去 都出去
- What, with Liz? - Out. Out. Everyone out.
妈妈 别这样 他没话要说 他不能...
Mama, please, he has nothing to say. He can't...
珍 别走 别 别...
Jane, please don't. Please, please...
伊丽莎白小姐 我一进这房子时
Miss Elizabeth, as soon as I entered the house
就选中了你来做我未来人生的伴侣
I singled you out as the companion for my future life.
别这样
Oh, no.
我相信娶了你会大大地增加我的幸福
I am convinced marrying you will add very greatly to my happiness.
但实际上我必须说的是
But, actually, I must add,
我当然会要你放弃武艺
I will of course require you to retire your warrior skills
来作为结婚的一部分条件
as part of the marital submission.
我们的家绝不能有武器
We absolutely can't have swords in the home.
现在 伊丽莎白小姐
And now, miss Elizabeth,
请允许我向你用最激动的话语
allow me to assure you in the most animated language
来表达我热烈的 最热烈的情感
of the violence, the sheer violence of my affections.
先生 我很荣幸被你求婚 谢谢
- Sir, I am honored by your proposal. - Thank you.
真的
I am,
但很遗憾 我必须拒绝
but I regret, I must refuse.
丽兹 我坚持要你嫁给柯林斯先生
Lizzy, I insist you marry Mr. Collins.
不行
No!
柯林斯先生 别担心
Do not worry, Mr. Collins.
我会让她明白的
She shall be brought to reason.
- 那就好 - 不行
- Oh, good. - No.
不要啊
Oh, no...
我深感抱歉
I'm terribly sorry.
伊丽莎白·班内特
Now, Elizabeth Bennet,
你回去  你回去
you get back there. You get back there.
- 不行 - 你要接受你未来的...
- No. - And you face up to your future...
- 请原谅 - 班内特老爷
- Excuse me. - Mr. Bennet!
你必须来让丽兹嫁给柯林斯先生 因为她拒绝接受他
You must come and make lizzy marry Mr. Collins, for she refuses to have him!
可恶
Bugger.
丽兹
Lizzy!
丽兹 你要嫁给柯林斯先生
Lizzy, you will marry Mr. Collins
不然我永远不和你说话了
or I shall never speak to you again!
你跟她说说
You talk to her.
丽兹 摆在你面前的是个不幸的难题
Lizzy! An unhappy alternative is before you.
你不嫁给柯林斯先生
Your mother will never speak to you again
你母亲就永远不和你说话了
if you do not marry Mr. Collins.
你嫁给他 我就永远不和你说话了
And I will never speak to you again if you do.
等你父亲过世了 谁会养你
Who will maintain you when your father is dead?
没人 伊丽莎白·班内特
No one, Elizabeth Bennet!
你会变成又穷又惨的老处女
You shall become a poor and pathetic spinster!
最不能
Anything.
最不能优先考虑或容忍的事
Anything is to be preferred or endured
就是和不爱的人结婚
rather than marrying without affection!
丽兹
Lizzy.
丽兹 别单独进树林
Lizzy, don't go into the woods alone!
丽兹
Lizzy!
我禁止你去
I forbid you!
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
韦翰先生?
Mr. wickham.
你在舞会上消失了
You vanished at the ball.
是的
Yes.
我觉得让达西先生遇见我 这样太自私了
I thought it would've been selfish of me to seek an encounter with Darcy.
会毁了在场所有人的舞会
Would've ruined the ball for anyone who witnessed it.
我很遗憾我没能和你跳舞 失去了该有的乐趣
I am very sorry i lost the pleasure of dancing with you, though.
你有恰好看到四名先生从这经过吗
Did you happen to see four gentlemen pass this way?
- 戴高顶帽的? - 你看见他们了?
- In top hats? - You saw them?
没有 但他们肯定是护柩人
No, but they were undoubtedly pallbearers.
这里是一个公墓
This is a cemetery.
班内特小姐
Uh, miss Bennet?
我想带你去一个对我来说非常特别的地方
I want to take you somewhere very special to me.
那是个秘密的地方 我从没带别的活人去过
It's a secret place I've never shown another living soul.
我第一次在中陆驻扎时
I stumbled upon it quite by accident
偶然发现了那里
when I was first stationed in the in-between.
但不知何故 我相信是上天注定要我发现的 班内特小姐
But somehow, I believe i was always destined to find it, miss Bennet.
你进去吧 我栓好马就来
You go in. I'll join you after I see to my horse.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
我没害怕
I'm not.
圣拉撒路
我带你们的祖先离开埃及
"And I brought your fathers out of Egypt.
来到海边
"And ye came unto the sea,
埃及人用战车和骑手把他们
"and the Egyptians crowded their fathers with chariots and horsemen
追到红海
"to the red sea.
他们哭求主时
"And when they cried unto the lord...
主将黑暗放于你们与埃及人之间
"...he put darkness between you and the Egyptians,
把这个带给了他们
"and brought this upon them.
信我的人
"He that believeth in me,
即使死了
"though he were dead,
也会复活
"yet shall he live."
你们太无礼了
You're quite rude.
耶稣大声喊道
"And Jesus cried out with a loud voice,
拉撒路 出来
"'Lazarus, come out!'"
别 住手
No, don't! Don't.
没事
It's all right.
蒙召来赴圣宴的是有福的
"Happy are those who are called to his supper.
蝗虫没有国王
"The locusts have no king.
然而它们全都成队行进
"Yet all of them go forth, marching in rank.
剪蝗剩下的 群蝗来吃
"What the cutting locust left, the swarming locust has eaten.
群蝗剩下的...
"What the swarming locust...
- 人脑 - 不是 那些是猪脑
- Brains. - No. They're pigs' brains.
没什么好怕的
You have nothing to fear.
你看 他们不吃人脑
You see, if they never consume human brains
就不会完全转化成僵尸
they will never fully transform into zombies.
圣拉撒路是终结
St. Lazarus is the key to finally ending
活人与活死人间争斗的关键
the struggle between the living and the undead.
我们必须和他们之中的精英
We must force some kind of understanding
促成某种协议
with the most advanced among them.
王室肯定会支持这样的尝试
Well, surely the crown will support such a venture.
战争几乎让大不列颠破产了
The war has almost bankrupted Great Britain.
我不知道投靠哪里
I know not where to turn.
他们的数量超过我们只是时间问题
It's only a matter of time before they outnumber us.
门口有骑手来了
Rider at the gate!
立正
Attention!
- 丽兹 - 夏洛特?
- Liz? - Charlotte?
我不知道你来拜访了
I didn't know you were coming to visit.
我有消息告诉你
I have some news.
我和柯林斯先生订婚了
I'm engaged to be married to Mr. Collins.
你一定很惊讶
You must be surprised.
没有 我解脱了
I'm not. I'm relieved.
我相信我和他婚后所能获得的幸福
I believe that my chance of happiness with him
会是大多数女人所希望的那样
is as fair as most women can hope for.
那就是你期望的?
And that's all you expect?
二十五岁 已比我期望的要好
At 25, it's more than I expect.
夏洛特 如果你高兴 那我也高兴
Charlotte, if you're happy for you, then I am, too.
我会被带去觐见凯瑟琳夫人
Well, I am to be presented to lady Catherine
在柯林斯先生的教区长住所过夜的话
and if I am to stay the night at Mr. Collins' rectory,
我要有个女伴
I will require a chaperone.
- 夏洛特... - 据说她是个大人物
- Charlotte... - She's said to be quite an imposing figure.
一想到要面对她而没你在 就让我紧张死了
And the thought of facing her without you makes me deathly nervous.
所以 求你了
So, please?
我会去的 但我有一个条件
I'll come, but I have one stipulation.
什么都行
Anything.
见凯瑟琳夫人时
Now, when we meet lady Catherine,
行简单的屈膝礼就好
a simple curtsey will suffice.
保持眼神接触 没人跟你讲话前 请不要讲话
Maintain eye contact, but don't speak unless spoken to, please.
凯瑟琳夫人最爱的黑色护卫队
Lady Catherine's famed black guard.
他们不准动
They can't move.
看这儿 你能用羽毛挠他
Here, look at this, you could tickle him with a feather. Oh!
把门降下
Lower the gate!
一个卓绝非凡的景象 对吗
An extraordinary sight, is it not? Oh!
太雄伟了
Such splendor.
凯瑟琳夫人之击杀活死人路西法
Lady Catherine smiting the undead lucifer.
太有气势了
Majestic. Oh!
伊丽莎白·班内特
Elizabeth Bennet.
僵尸末日四骑士
The four horsemen of the zombie apocalypse.
他们出现时 末日就到来了
When they appear, the end of days is neigh.
小姐 这边请
This way, miss.
柯林斯牧师 卢卡斯小姐和班内特小姐来了
Parson Collins, miss Lucas, and miss Bennet.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
凯瑟琳夫人
Lady Catherine.
德·包尔小姐
Miss de bourgh.
凯瑟琳夫人
Lady Catherine.
你就是伊丽莎白·班内特
So you are Elizabeth Bennet.
是的 夫人阁下
Um, yes. I am, your ladyship.
这是我的女儿
This is my daughter.
凯瑟琳夫人 你邀请我们来喝茶
Well, it's very kind of you
真的是太好了
to invite us over for tea, lady Catherine. Really.
非常感激
Very grateful.
达西先生?
Mr. Darcy?
班内特小姐
Miss Bennet.
我认识我的侄子?
You know my nephew?
是的 在哈福德郡认识他
Yes, I had the tremendous pleasure
我莫大的荣幸
of meeting him in Hertfordshire.
韦翰先生来了
Mr. wickham.
- 你说的是那个士兵吗 - 是的
- Is this the soldier you spoke of? - Yes.
班内特小姐请他来的
Miss Bennet requested he attend,
他要和夫人阁下商讨
that he might confer with your ladyship
对抗天灾的策略
about a strategy with which to combat the scourge.
一名中尉?真的吗
Mmm, a lieutenant? Really?
确实
Indeed.
茶送来了
And tea is brought up.
- 去喝吧- 非常乐意
- Oh! Shall we?  - Oh, delighted to.
来
Please.
我已把你引见给了国内最富有的女人
I have given you entry to the wealthiest woman in the kingdom.
其他就看你的了
The rest is up to you.
夫人阁下或许听说过
Your ladyship has perhaps heard
一些受袭者没有屈服于
that some of the stricken have not succumbed
想吃活人的欲望
to the urge to feed upon the living,
他们就这样保留了人类行为
and in so doing have maintained their human ways.
他们怎么忍住
And they have managed to resist this
这种最原始的僵尸欲望的
most primal of zombie urges, how?
靠他们的金规铁律?
Their iron-clad constitutions?
是的 靠对信仰的虔诚和猪脑来坚定意志
Yes, fortified by religious piety and pigs' brains,
把猪脑当成基督圣血那样领受圣餐
which they receive in communion as the blood of Christ.
以此抑制他们对人脑的欲望
The pig brains quench their appetite for human brains.
是啊 当然
Oh, yes, of course.
王室的资金已经耗尽了
The crown's funds have been drained.
你是来募集资金的?
You're here to solicit money?
我是来提议一个尝试 来永远终结这场战争
I am here to propose a venture that would end the war forever.
这些新的僵尸明理通达
These new zombies can be reasoned with.
有了适当的资金 我相信我们能
With the proper funding, i believe we can cultivate trust
和新的迭代活死人建立信任 甚至友好
and even goodwill with this new iteration of the undead,
他们似乎有一种高于
who seem to possess an inherent power
他们低级同类的固有权利
over the lower ranks of their kind.
僵尸贵族?
Zombie aristocrats?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我更倾向于把他们当做迷失在炼狱的灵魂
I prefer to think of them as souls lost in purgatory.
普通族群依赖他们的领导
The common hordes look to them for leadership.
只要其中一个意识到了他们的能力
It takes just one of them to realize their power
然后率众族群作战...
and then to lead the hordes into battle...
- 活死人就像蝗虫一样 - 蝗虫
- The undead are like locusts. - Locusts.
他们四处破坏 他们要领袖没用
They go forth and destroy. They have no use for leaders.
其实有一个例外
Oh, um, except one. Actually.
其实按《启示录》的说法
Oh, well, um, according to the book of revelation, actually,
敌基督会在人类末日的那一天
the antichrist shall lead the undead
领导活死人
on the day that shall be the last day of mankind.
- 真让人鼓舞啊 柯林斯 - 谢谢 凯瑟琳夫人
- How cheery, Collins. - Thank you, lady Catherine.
真慷慨 福林克林 还有烤饼吗
Very generous. Franklin, are there more scones?
我们可以磋商 和一组选定的...
If we could negotiate with this select group of...
贵族?为了什么呢
Aristocrats? To what end?
一份协定
A treaty.
绥靖?
Appeasement?
绝不
Never.
那人类肯定会灭亡
Well, then the human race is surely doomed.
夫人阁下 活死人的增长
Your ladyship, the undead will always multiply faster
一直比活人繁殖快
than the living can procreate.
一个小孩出生要9个月生
Nine months to make a baby,
成为士兵要16年
then 16 years to make a soldier,
而变僵尸只要一秒
and one raw second to make a zombie.
你必须意识到 他们组织起来的话 我们就无法击败他们
You must realize, if they were to organize, we cannot defeat them.
唯一的希望是在他们找到敌基督前
The only hope is to find a way to coexist with them,
找一个办法和他们共存
before they find their antichrist.
老达西先生会支持这样的尝试
The late Mr. Darcy would have supported such a venture.
韦翰 我容忍你出现在此够久了
I have tolerated your presence here long enough, wickham.
护卫
Guards.
请铭记这一刻
Please do remember this moment,
还有这个被你们直接摒弃的机会
and the opportunity so glibly spurned.
僵尸之日已经到来
The day of the zombie has already broken.
要么醒来面对曙光 要么沉睡在湮没之中
Wake and face the light, or slumber into oblivion.
达西先生 你和活死人一样无情
Mr. Darcy, you are as unfeeling as the undead.
我的看法是
My word,
你这样的年轻人 说话太武断了
you give your opinion very decidedly for so young a person.
确实 凯瑟琳夫人
Indeed, lady Catherine.
我想说 安女士今早
Well, I would like to say how dutifully behaved I think
真是尽心尽责
lady Anne has been this morning.
为家族尽显殊荣
A real credit to the crest, actually.
亲爱的 你要一块烤饼吗
Would you like a scone, dear?
我不是有意吓唬你
I didn't mean to frighten you.
你没吓到我
You didn't.
肯定没有
No. Of course not.
罗新斯是英格兰最安全的地方
Rosings is the safest place in england.
你看问题就在这里
You see, that's the problem.
贵族都觉得他们在豪宅内不可战胜
Aristos feel invincible within their great houses,
但他们大错特错了
but how wrong they are.
他们的狂妄会使他们垮台
Their hubris will be their downfall.
垮台?
"Downfall"?
你说得好像活死人已经击败了我们似的
You act as if the undead had already defeated us.
丽兹·班内特 我认为我们彼此理解对方
I think you and i understand each other, Liz Bennet.
你之前那么支持我
Well, the way you championed me earlier, i thought...
达西先生一直极为卑鄙地对待你 但是...
Mr. Darcy's treatment of you has been utterly despicable, but...
他对待你和你的家人更为卑鄙
No more despicable than his treatment of you and your family.
先生 我不明白你在说什么
I don't understand you, sir.
劝宾利远离你姐姐并离开尼日斐的人是达西
It was Darcy that persuaded Bingley to stay clear of your sister and leave Netherfield.
为什么
Why?
因为他认为你姐姐配不上他的朋友
Because he believes your sister be inferior to his friend.
达西还使宾利相信
Darcy also convinced Bingley
她贪图的是他的财富 而不是真的爱他
that she is after his fortune and doesn't truly love him.
你怎么可能知道这些
How could you possibly know this?
男人间的传言
Men talk.
达西跟他的密友夸耀过这些事
Darcy brags about it with his intimates.
班内特小姐 和我私奔吧
Miss Bennet, run away with me.
先生 你越界了
You have crossed a line, sir.
班内特小姐 我们现在远没越界
We're far beyond lines now, miss Bennet.
班内特小姐  留心牧师吧
Take heed of the parson, miss Bennet.
清算日来临了
The day of reckoning is upon us.
夏洛特
Charlotte?
- 达西先生 - 班内特小姐
- Mr. Darcy. - Miss Bennet.
你终于起床了 真是万幸
You've finally arisen. How fortuitous.
有些话 我必须说
There are some words i must say.
请坐下说
Please do be seated.
班内特小姐 虽然我知道很多人认为
Miss Bennet, although I know many consider you to be decidedly inferior,
你的出生 家庭和条件都较为低下
as a matter of your birth, your family, and your circumstances,
而我克制不住我的情感了
my feelings will not be repressed.
我的内心挣扎过
In vain have I struggled.
从认识你开始 我就对你有了一份最热切的
I have come to feel for you a most ardent admiration and regard,
爱慕和敬意 它们打败了我的理智
which has overcome my better judgment.
因此现在我以最热忱之情恳求你
So now I ask you most fervently
解除我的痛苦 答应做我的妻子
to end my turmoil and consent to be my wife.
如果我觉得值得感激 那我现在就会谢谢你
If I could feel gratitude, i would now thank you,
但我不这么觉得
but I cannot.
我不曾渴求过你的好感
I never desired your good opinion,
而你这么做无疑是心不甘情不愿
and you have certainly bestowed it most unwillingly.
能告诉我为什么吗
Might I be informed why,
为什么我会受到这么没有礼貌的拒绝
with so little endeavor at civility, i am rejected?
你有意毁了我挚爱姐姐的幸福
You intentionally ruined the happiness of my most beloved sister.
- 你否认吗 - 我不想否认
- Do you deny it? - I have no wish to deny it.
我用了我能力之内的一切办法让我朋友和你姐姐分开
I did everything in my power to separate my friend from your sister.
你怎么能这样
How could you?
因为我认为宾利对她的感情
Because I perceived his attachment to her
远比她对宾利的要深
to be far deeper than hers to him.
我认为她很冷漠
I believed her to be indifferent.
冷漠?她是害羞啊
Indifferent? She's shy!
你是不是向宾利先生
Did you suggest to Mr. Bingley
提过这和他的财富有关
that his fortune had some bearing on the matter?
我不会对你姐姐做让她有失脸面的事
I wouldn't do your sister the dishonor,
虽然是有人提过
though it was suggested.
宾利小姐提的?
By miss Bingley?
是你母亲在舞会上提的
By your mother, at the ball.
好几个月前 韦翰先生就向我透露过你的品格
Your character was revealed to me many months ago by wickham
他耻辱般的不幸都拜你所赐
as I heard of his scandalous misfortunes at your hand.
韦翰先生确实非常不幸
Oh, yeah. Mr. wickham's misfortunes have been very great indeed.
他被指定享有的利益 你知道却不给他
You withhold the advantages that you know were designed for him.
这就是你对我的看法?
This is your opinion of me?
那我谢谢你解释得这么充分
Then I thank you for explaining it so fully.
你用尽一切办法
You could not have made the offer of your hand
也没法打动我接受你的求婚
in any possible way that would have tempted me to accept it.
我认识你一个月都不到
I had not known you a month
就觉得即便你是世上最后一个男人
before I felt that you were the last man in the world
我也绝不会嫁给你
whom I could ever be prevailed on to marry.
女士 你说得够多的了
You've said quite enough, madam.
我完全理解你的感受
I fully comprehend your feelings
现在我只对自己感到羞耻
and now have only to be ashamed of what my own have been.
请原谅我 也请接受我对你健康
Please forgive me, and accept my best wishes
和幸福的至诚祝福
for your health and happiness.
你好 下午好 回来真好
Hello. Good afternoon. Wonderful to be back.
天呐
Oh, heavens.
丽兹 发生什么事了
What happened, lizzy?
这可是古董 独一无二的
This is an antique. Irreplaceable.
凯瑟琳夫人亲自送给我的
Lady Catherine herself delivered this to me.
- 达西先生... - 来自中国海滨
- Mr. Darcy... - It's from the shores of China.
达西先生来过农舍了?
Mr. Darcy came by the cottage?
来过这里?
Came here?
太好了
Fabulous.
伊丽莎白小姐 这里会被收拾好的
This will need clearing up, Elizabeth.
亲爱的伊丽莎白·班内特小姐
"Dear miss Elizabeth Bennet,
我不会再提
"i am not writing to renew the sentiments
令你十分厌恶的情感
"which were so disgusting to you,
但我想解释你对我的两项指责
"but to address the two offenses that you accused me of.
我不是故意要伤害你的姐姐
"I did not intentionally wound your sister.
那是为了保护我最要好的朋友
"It was a most unfortunate consequence
而造成的最不幸的后果
"of protecting my dearest friend.
宾利先生对班内特小姐的感情
"Mr. Bingley's feelings for miss Bennet
是我在他身上前所未见的
"were beyond any I had ever witnessed in him,
甚至是他无法自已的
"or indeed even thought him capable of.
在尼日斐舞会那晚
"The evening of the dance at Netherfield,
我偶然听到你母亲冷冷地说到
"after overhearing your mother coldly state her intention
她要所有女儿嫁给富人的意图
"of having all her daughtes marry favorably,
之后 我劝说了宾利 让他相信他俩不般配
"i persuaded Bingley of the unfitness of the match.
对班内特小姐情感上的伤害 是我的无心之过
"If I have wounded miss Bennet's feelings, it was unknowingly done.
至于你指责我对韦翰先生的伤害
"As to your other accusation, of having injured Mr. wickham,
在我的父亲达西先生明确表明
"no sooner had my father made clear his intention
要留给韦翰先生一笔数目可观的金钱后
"to leave Mr. wickham a handsome sum,
他就立马神秘地被感染了瘟疫
"than Mr. Darcy was mysteriously infected by the plague.
而他则由他的儿子 我 帮他善了终
"It was left to me, his son, to provide a merciful ending.
然而 我还是给了韦翰我父亲留给他的遗产
"Still, I gave wickham the inheritance my father left.
韦翰却挥霍光了
"Wickham squandered it.
之后他便索要越来越多的钱
"Whereupon he demanded more and more money,
直到我最终拒绝
"until I eventually refuse.
此后他和我断绝了一切联系
"Thereafter he severed all ties with me.
去年夏天 他和我15岁的妹妹展开了一段感情
"Last summer he began a relationship with my 15-year-old sistr
并劝她私奔
"and convinced her to elop.
韦翰先生主要是看上了
"Mr. wickham's prime target
她继承的3万英镑
"was her inheritance of £30,000,
不过他的另一个强烈动机是为了报复我
"but revenging himself on me was a strong additional inducement.
幸好我及时说服了我妹妹
"Fortunately, I was able to persuade my sister
使她相信韦翰先生
"of Mr. wickham's ulterior motives
另有所图
"before it was too late.
我希望这些能帮我解释
"I hope this helps explan
或许也能多少改变你对我的看法
"and perhaps mitigate my behavior in your eyes.
现在我知道了
"Of all the weapons in the world,
世界上最危险的武器是爱
"i now know love to be the most dangerous.
因为我遭受了致命创伤
"For I have suffered a mortal wound.
班内特小姐 我无法确定是什么时间或地点
"When did I fall so deeply under your spell, miss Bennet?
看到了你什么样的容貌或谈吐
"I cannot fix the hour or the spot
使我被你的魅力所深深折服
"or the look or the words which laid the foundation.
等我发觉我爱上你时 我已深陷其中
"I was in the middle before I knew I had began.
我是一个多么傲慢的傻瓜啊
"What a proud fool I was.
我面对的是一个残酷事实
"I have faced the harsh truth,
我这辈子再也没法指望赢得你的芳心
"that I can never hope to win your love in this life,
所以我便投入战斗 寻求慰藉
"and so have sought solace in combat.
我在被围攻的伦敦给你写信
"I write to you from the siege of London.
现在僵尸来袭 这是一项狡诈的计划
"There is now a cunning design to the zombie attacks.
班内特小姐 我感觉到这里
"I sense a dark hand is at work here,
有一只黑手在操纵 指挥着敌人
"guiding the enemy, miss Bennet.
攻打伦敦使他们增加了百倍队列
"By taking London, they've increased their ranks a hundred fold.
加把劲 伙计们
Come on, lads!
现在我们尽力把他们困在高墙内
"Now we endeavor to keep them trapped within the great wall."
这可不是一个愚蠢族群的随意行动
This wasn't the random act of a mindless horde.
他们攻击了宫殿和两院
They've struck the palace and both houses.
他们要在我们砍下他们的头之前 杀掉我们的首脑
They cut off our head before we could cut off theirs.
继续战斗
Keep fighting.
加把劲 伙计们
Come on, men!
倘若我们没牵制住他们 让他们突破了欣厄姆桥
"If we should fail to contain them and they breach hingham bridge,
那就会像大坝垮塌
"it'll be as if a great dam has broken,
他们对哈福德郡便唾手可及
"and they'll reach Hertfordshire swiftly.
涌入的僵尸将不计其数
"And in overwhelming numbers.
亲爱的班内特小姐 我恳求你做好准备
"Dear miss Bennet, I implore you to be ready."
丽兹
Lizzy!
- 丽兹 - 珍
Liz! Jane!
珍 珍 怎么了
Jane... Jane, what is it?
韦翰和莉迪亚私奔了
Wickham's run off with Lydia.
她几乎还是个孩子
She's barely more than a child.
我从没想到这个人如此不道德
I never could have imagined the man to be so improper,
如此居心叵测
to be such a blaggard.
我们该怎么办
What are we to do?
圣拉撒路
St. Lazarus.
我知道她在哪
I know where she is.
你们的庄园真是小
You have a very small estate here.
但还是能容下我们
And yet we endure it.
我有急事在身
I have urgent business to attend to.
有一则最为可耻的流言传到了我的耳中
A falsehood of a most scandalous nature has reached me,
你打算和我的侄子达西先生结婚
that you intend to be united with my own nephew, Mr. Darcy.
这是真的吗
Is this true?
夫人阁下 我不想像你一样率直
I do not possess your frankness, your ladyship.
但你可以问 我也可以不回答
You may ask questions, i may not choose to answer.
班内特小姐  我来把话说明白
Let me be rightly understood, miss Bennet.
达西和我女儿是娃娃亲
Darcy has been promised since infancy to my daughter.
那你没理由认为他向我求婚了
Well, then you can have no reason to suppose he made me an offer.
你有没有和他订婚
Are you engaged to him or not?
没有
I'm not.
你能否向我保证绝不和他订婚
And will you promise me never to enter into such an engagement?
我不会做这种保证
I will make no such promise.
那我得捍卫一个高贵男人的尊严
Then I shall protect the dignity of a far superior man.
你敢和我决斗吗
Do you dare to face me in combat?
不敢
I do not.
夫人阁下 拿武器对抗你
For to take arms against you, my lady,
就是拿武器对抗英格兰
would be to take arms against england.
说得很对
Quite right.
我的代表就足够了
My proxy will have to suffice.
威尔海姆
Wilhelm.
班内特小姐 你让步吗
Miss Bennet, do you concede?
不让
I do not.
每次受到威胁 我总会更为无畏
My courage always rises at every attempt to intimidate me.
你仍然拒绝帮我这个忙吗
Do you still refuse to oblige me?
是的
I do!
伊丽莎白·班内特 我不知道我更欣赏你哪一点
I do not know which I admire more, Elizabeth Bennet.
是你作为战士的武艺
Your skill as a warrior,
还是你作为女人的决绝
or your resolve as a woman.
爸爸 她在中陆
They've got her in the in-between, papa.
莉迪亚的声誉岌岌可危
Lydia's honor is at stake.
丽兹 制止他 他要去找莉迪亚和韦翰
Stop him, Liz. He's going after Lydia and wickham.
慢着 爸爸
Wait, papa.
做对的事都不会嫌早
What's right to be done cannot be done too soon.
可你都不知道她在哪 而我知道
But you don't even know where she is. I do.
我保证我不会不管莉迪亚
I promise you i won't forsake Lydia.
我跟你一起去
I'll go with you.
不行 你必须待在这里 保卫朗伯恩
No, you must stay here to help protect longbourn.
你们两个快上马吧
Ride at once. Both of you.
我会带你剩余的家人和我回罗新斯
I will take the rest of your family back with me to rosings.
英格兰没有比之更安全的地方了
There's no safer place in england.
集合你的家人
Collect your people.
这座桥禁行了
This bridge is closed!
过去太危险了
It's too dangerous to cross.
整个伦敦已陷入僵尸之手
All of London's fallen to the zombies.
我们在另一边有急事
We have urgent business on the other side.
这座桥安置了
This bridge is rigged
英格兰剩余的所有炸药
with all the explosives left in england.
明天最后一支中队
It's to be detonated tomorrow at dawn
从中陆撤出后的黎明之时会引爆
when the last squadron withdraw from the in-between.
我们的小伙子们守不了多久
Our boys can't hold them much longer.
如果伦敦的活死人夺取了这座桥
If the undead of London take the bridge,
那么英格兰余下的地方无疑也会不保
the rest of england will surely be lost.
即便如此 我们也必须过去
Nevertheless, we must cross over.
实行僵尸协议
Zombie protocols in effect!
一 找出并消灭任何剩余的活死人
One, seek out and destroy any remaining undead.
二 任何阵亡者的完好头骨
Two, any of the fallen with intact skulls
必须被刺穿或压碎大脑
must have their brains perforated or crushed
来确保他们不会像活死人那样死而复生
to ensure they do not rise again as the undead!
真该死 该死的围巾
Bloody hell... Fie, damnable scarf!
你好 班内特小姐
Hello, miss Bennet.
公共墓地
Potter's field.
是的 没错
Yes. Quite.
什么
Pardon?
这里 我们所站的地方
This. What we're standing on,
是一个无标示的僵尸墓地
it's an unmarked zombie graveyard.
是的 当然
Yes. Of course.
班内特小姐 你们俩怎么
Miss Bennet, what possible cause could the two of you have
离开哈福德郡进入中陆了
for leaving Hertfordshire and entering into the in-between?
如果艳遇没降至一位年轻女士所在的村庄
If adventures will not befall a young lady in her own village,
那她一定会外出寻找
she must seek them abroad.
我们别无选择
We had no choice.
韦翰和莉迪亚私奔了
Wickham has run off with Lydia.
他把她带去了他的"僵尸贵族"聚集地
He has taken her to where his "zombie aristocrats" congregate.
圣拉撒路
St. Lazarus.
圣拉撒路?
St. Lazarus?
我很清楚
I know it well.
五天前 我看到它被夷为了平地
I saw it razed to the ground five days ago.
你妹妹不可能幸存
Your sister couldn't possibly have survived.
我对你失去亲人深表遗憾
I'm profoundly sorry for your loss.
达西上校
Colonel Darcy.
我们需要你去指挥营
We need you at the command tent.
我恐怕我必须立即动身去欣厄姆桥
I fear I must depart for hingham bridge immediately.
当然
Of course.
我们来看看那些贵族们
Let's see how reasonable his aristocrats are
被刺激食欲后 还有多么明理通达
after their appetites have been whet.
听我口令
On my mark.
现在
Now.
明天五点破晓时分
Dawn breaks at 5:00 tomorrow.
我会回来
I'll make it back.
你当然会 老兄
Of course you will, old man.
出现第一道曙光就必须下令
The order must be given at first light.
无论什么情况
No matter what.
我会下令的
I'll give the order.
我想我不该向达西透露的
I fear I should not have confided in Darcy.
担心一大群饿坏的那种东西吧 挤满了我们的路
Fear the hordes of ravenous unmentionables that are swarming our way.
丽兹 我们说话之时 伦敦已经陷落 巨垒满是烈火
Liz, London has already fallen and the grand barrier burns as we speak.
欣厄姆桥在我们身后
Hingham bridge is behind us.
伦敦在那边
London's over there.
宾利先生 你看的是哪个方向
Which direction are you looking in, Mr. Bingley?
圣拉撒路?
St. Lazarus?
- 达西撒谎了 - 为了保住你的命
- Darcy lied... - To spare you.
班内特小姐 他愿为你赴汤蹈火
He'd risk anything for you, miss Bennet.
丽兹 丽兹
Lizzy!Lizzy!
别磨蹭
Don't hang about.
继续
Go on.
士兵们不会那么干
Soldiers wouldn't do that.
我也不会...
Nor would I...
什么人会偷死亡士兵的大脑
Who would steal the brains of dead soldiers?
全能的拉撒路 所有的灵魂都向你敞开
Almighty Lazarus, to whom all souls are open.
放入你的神圣之灵 将生命注入我们心中
Breathe life into our hearts, by the insertion of your divine spirit.
复活在我 生命也在我
"I am the resurrection and the life.
信我的人...
"He that believeth in me..."
- 达西先生... - 没事了
- Mr. Darcy... - It's all right.
他说你会来 韦翰说你会来
He said you'd come. Wickham said you'd come.
达西先生
Mr. Darcy...
伦敦攻势
进攻计划
混蛋
Bastard.
天呐 你真是不出所料
My god, you're so predictable.
我知道带走小莉迪亚之后 你一定会捍卫班内特家的声誉
I knew by taking young Lydia, you'd have to protect the Bennets' honor.
那么 是来杀我的吗 菲茨
So, come to kill me then, Fitz?
正相反
On the contrary,
我是来给你一个提议的
I've come to make you an offer.
班内特家委任我
The Bennets have authorized me
提供你一万英镑的赎金
to offer you a commission of £10,000
以此来交还莉迪亚并永远离开英格兰
to return Lydia and leave england for good.
菲茨 你真高尚 来帮班内特家传达提议
How noble of you to deliver the Bennets' offer, Fitz,
但我恐怕我的回答是不行
but I'm afraid my answer is no.
乔治 不行是因为钱少
And is there no financial inducement
没法说服你做高尚的事吗
that could convince you to do the honorable thing, George?
不是
None.
你看 现在钱对我没用了
You see, money is of no use to me now.
那是你父亲的表吗
Is that your father's watch?
是的
Yes.
把它给我
Give it to me.
不行
No.
真该死
Bloody hell!
达西先生 救我
Mr. Darcy, please!
达西 你干了什么
What have you done, Darcy?
我喂了他们
I fed them!
乔治 愿上帝保佑你
Godspeed, Georgie.
你们所有人 去桥那儿 就现在 去桥那儿
All of you, go to the bridge! Now! Go to the bridge!
莉迪亚 听我说 你必须通过欣厄姆桥
Lydia, listen to me. You have to get across hingham bridge.
- 但是 达西先生 你得一起走 - 只要韦翰活着
- But Mr. Darcy, you have to come. - As long as wickham lives,
英格兰就危在旦夕 走吧 莉迪亚 快走
england is in peril. Go, Lydia. Go!
你们所有人 去欣厄姆桥
All of you, hingham bridge!
达西 我征服了伦敦
I conquered London, Darcy.
你真以为你能击败我?
Did you really think you could defeat me?
一向的
I always have.
乔治 你是个叛徒
You're a traitor, George.
错 菲茨 我是个国王
No, Fitz. I'm a king!
天呐
Oh, my god.
莉迪亚
Lydia!
长官 到时间了
It's time, sir.
的确到了
So it is.
- 有骑手 - 等下
- Rider! - Wait!
莉迪亚 其他人呢
Lydia, where are the others?
你个蠢货 我一直是他们的一员
You fool. I've been one of them all along.
如果我得到了你父亲想给我的牧师职位
If I had the living your father intended me,
我就绝不会参军
I never would have been in the army,
我就绝不会被感染
I never would have been infected.
达西 这是你做的好事
This is your doing, Darcy!
抑制我的饥饿很容易
Suppressing my hunger was easy.
他们需要神 而我用我对你的仇恨来支撑我
They needed god, i had my hatred of you to sustain me.
四骑士已从地狱崛起
The four horsemen have risen from hell!
僵尸末世到来了
The zombie apocalypse is here.
我是活死人一直等待的那个人
I am the one the undead have been waiting for.
那个统领他们的人
The one to lead them.
我夺取的每一条生命 我所做的每一个暴行
Every life I take, every atrocity I commit,
都算到你头上
is on your head!
保持警惕 伙计们
Keep your eyes peeled, lads!
- 长官 我们不能再拖了 - 不行
- We can't delay any longer, sir. - No!
活死人很快会突破桥梁 到时候就太迟了
The undead will have reached the bridge soon, and then it will be too late.
宾利 他们还没回来 你必须等等
They're not back yet! You must wait, Bingley!
引爆桥梁吧
Detonate the bridge.
下令 下令
Give the order. Give the order.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
四
Four!
三
Three!
二
Two!
一
One!
丽兹
Liz!
达西先生
Mr. Darcy.
我第一次看见你的那一刻
The very first moment i beheld you,
我的心就已无法收回了
my heart was irrevocably gone.
把门升起
Raise the gate!
凯瑟琳夫人 我能趁这个机会
Lady Catherine, might i take this opportunity
称赞你的裤子吗
to compliment you on your pantaloons?
还有你的眼罩 很迷人 是功能型还是装饰型?
And your eye patch. It's very fetching. Is it function or fashion?
功能型
Function.
夫人阁下
Your ladyship.
猜猜谁在图书馆里和爸爸说 是...
Guess who's speaking with papa in the library? It's...
宾利先生来了
Mr. Bingley.
凯瑟琳夫人
Lady Catherine.
这样真是尴尬
This is all rather embarrassing,
但我想请你特许我和珍小姐
but I would like to request the privilege of speaking with miss Jane.
私下谈话
Alone.
达西先生来了
Mr. Darcy.
我最爱的侄子
My favorite nephew,
你昏迷了好久
who lay unconscious for so long,
我们听说你会复苏时 我们还担心
that when we heard you'd risen, we'd feared
你会加入活死人的队列
you'd joined the ranks of the undead.
有运河那儿的消息吗
Any word from the canal?
暂时能守住
It's holding for the time being.
愿意
Yes!
珍说了愿意
Jane said yes.
请恕我失陪
Would you excuse me?
快 快 快
Quick! Quick, quick!
好激动啊
This is so exciting!
珍
Jane!
走啊 快点 莉迪亚
Keep going! Hurry up, Lydia!
班内特小姐
Miss Bennet.
达西先生
Mr. Darcy.
看样子你彻底痊愈了
You look as though you're fully mended.
是的 谢谢
I am. Thank you.
如果不是你 我肯定必死无疑
If it wasn't for you, I'd have surely perished.
你在很多方面拯救了我
You have saved me in more ways than one.
你在欣厄姆桥上跟我说的话...
What you said to me on hingham bridge...
你听到了?
You heard me?
是的
I did.
给了我希望
It gave me hope.
什么希望
Of what?
你对我的看法或许改变了
That your feelings towards me may have changed.
然而你的一句话
However, one word from you now
会让我永远不再提此话题
will silence me on this subject forever.
伊丽莎白·班内特 你是我的毕生挚爱
You are the love of my life, Elizabeth Bennet.
所以 我现在 一半焦虑 一半憧憬地问你
So I ask you now, half in anguish, half in hope,
你愿意给我莫大的荣幸
will you do me the great, great honor
让我做你的丈夫吗
of taking me for your husband?
愿意
Yes.
亲爱的各位
Dearly beloved,
今天 我们在上帝的注视下 聚集于此
we are gathered here tody in the sight of god
来一同见证 这位先生和这位女士
to join together this man and this woman,
以及这位先生和这位女士
and this man and this woman,
他们的神圣婚礼
in holy matrimony.
现在我宣布你们结为夫妻
I now pronounce you man and wife,
还有你们也结为夫妻
and man and wife.
达西先生 现在你们可以亲吻新娘了
You may now kiss Mr. Darcy... The brides.
现在你们可以亲吻新娘了
You may now kiss the brides.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢临场
Thank you for coming.
我好高兴
I'm so happy!